Guide to the Natalini Superstudio Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Natalini Superstudio collection
1967-2012
GEN MSS 796
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.67
(5 boxes) + 11 broadsides
The Natalini Superstudio Collection documents the career of Adolfo Natalini and the experimental group Superstudio. There is also abundant material relating to other radical architectural groups and projects of the 1960s and 1970s, including Archigram, Archizoom, 9999, and Global Tools. The collection consists of both manuscript and printed material. The former includes original drawings, collages, photographs, and artwork as well as typescript or mimeographed circulars and documents relating to Superstudio's activities and conceptual projects from 1967, as well as Natalini's individual development and architectural work continuing after the group's dissolution in 1986. Printed material includes exhibition catalogs, manifestos, posters, and articles published in avant-garde architectural and design journals as well as interviews, conference proceedings, and monographs about the work of Natalini and Superstudio through the mid-2000s.
Natalini, Adolfo, 1941-
Superstudio (Group)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Argenario Studio Bibliografico on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Superstudio
Superstudio was an experimental Italian architecture collective founded by Adolfo Natalini and Cristiano Toraldo di Francia in Florence and active from 1966-1978.
Adolfo Natalini
Adolfo Natalini (born 1941) is an Italian architect, artist, and designer. He co-founded the experimental group Superstudio with Cristiano Toraldo di Francia and others in Florence in 1966.
Scope and Contents
The Natalini Superstudio Collection documents the career of Adolfo Natalini and the experimental group Superstudio. There is also abundant material relating to other radical architectural groups and projects of the 1960s and 1970s, including Archigram, Archizoom, 9999, and Global Tools. The collection consists of both manuscript and printed material. The former includes original drawings, collages, photographs, and artwork as well as typescript or mimeographed circulars and documents relating to Superstudio's activities and conceptual projects from 1967, as well as Natalini's individual development and architectural work continuing after the group's dissolution in 1986. Printed material includes exhibition catalogs, manifestos, posters, and articles published in avant-garde architectural and design journals as well as interviews, conference proceedings, and monographs about the work of Natalini and Superstudio through the mid-2000s.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: March 2011 Acquisition; September 2012 Acquisition.
Architecture -- Italy; Architecture, Modern -- 20th Century; Architectural design -- Italy; Avant-garde (Aesthetics) -- Italy; Collages (visual works) -- Italy -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- Italy -- 20th Century; Photographs -- Italy -- 20th Century; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941-; Toraldo di Francia, Cristiano, 1941-; 9999 (Firm); Archigram (Group); Archizoom associati; Global tools; Superstudio (Group)
- March 2011 Acquisition, 1967-2010
  Arrangement
  Arranged by dealer catalog number, except for serials, which are grouped by title.
  - Adolfo Natalini: Dal Superstudio all'architettura di resistenza, 2011; Arengario studio bibliografico (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Dealer catalog for the March 2011 acquisition created by Argenario Studio Bibliografico.
  - Superarchitettura é una mostra della galleria del Comune di Modena dal 19 marzo al 12 april 1967 ... / Archizoom e Superstudio, marzo 1967. [Modena: s.n., 1967], Catalog # 1 (Box 5 (Broadside))
    Other Finding Aids
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9900550.
  - Archigram. 8(1968) London, Archigram., Catalog # 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/479787.
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.473(1969:apr.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/472090.
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.475(1969:guigno) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.479(1969:ott.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.481(1969:dic.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.489(1970:ag.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.491(1970:ott.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.509(1972:apr.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 37 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.517(1972:dic.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 47 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Domus: arte e stile nella casa, arte e stile nell'industria (industrial design). n.540(1974:nov.) [Milano: s.n., 1928- ], Catalog # 60 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Casa Vogue. n.2(1969:guigno) Milano: Edizioni Condé Nast, Catalog # 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9884822.
  - Casa Vogue. n.89(1978:dic.) Milano: Edizioni Condé Nast, Catalog # 68 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Drawing for "Paesaggi. Monumento continuo", 1969; Catalog # 6; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 6 (Broadside))
  - Drawings for "Il monumento continuo a Firenze - Due progetti per Palazzo Pitti", 1969; Catalog # 7; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 7 (Broadside))
  - Trigon '69 [i.e. neunundsechzig]: Architektur und Freiheit [Ausstellung im] Künstlerhaus Graz, 4 Okt. bis 15 Nov., 1969. [Katalogredaktion: Wilfried Skreiner und Horst Gerhard Haberl. Übersetzer: Maria Kiefer. Graz, 1969], Catalog # 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/3688789.
  - Postcard, "Liebe Grüsse aus Graz von Superstudio," signed by Adolfo Natalini, 1969; Catalog # 10; Superstudio (Group) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Drawings for "(New York) Il monumento continuo - Tre schizzi", 1969; Catalog # 12; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 8 (Broadside))
  - Drawing of Superstudio logo, 1970; Catalog # 13; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 101)
  - Progetto Print. 1969/70 "La superficie neutra, 1970; Catalog # 15; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jyapan interia = Japan interior design. no.138(1970:Sept.) Tokyo: Gakurin Inc., Catalog # 16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/1612815.
  - Jyapan interia = Japan interior design. no.140(1970:Nov.) Tokyo: Gakurin Inc., Catalog # 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Jyapan interia = Japan interior design. no.144(1971:Mar.) Tokyo: Gakurin Inc., Catalog # 25 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jyapan interia = Japan interior design. no.164(1972:Nov.) Tokyo: Gakurin Inc., Catalog # 44 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Istogrammi d'architettura [graphic]: con riferimento a un reticolo trasponibile in aree o scale diverse per l'edificazione di una natura serena e immobile in cui riconoscersi / Superstudio 1969. [Milano: Superstudio, 1969] (Milano: Plura edizioni), Catalog # 19; Superstudio (Group) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9885305.
  - [Photograph of a tile box with a mirror bottom reflecting the sky, on a bed of rubble] [graphic] [Italy: s.n., ca. 1969?], Catalog # 20 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9885368.
  - Un viaggio nelle regioni della ragione [graphic] ... / Superstudio 1968-69 (l. continua). [Milano: Superstudio, 1969] (Milano: Plura edizioni), Catalog # 21; Superstudio (Group) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9885962.
  - Niagara o l'architettura reflessa [graphic]: dalla seconda serie della natura ... / Superstudio 1970. [Milano: Superstudio, 1970] (Milano: Plura edizioni), Catalog # 22 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9886614.
  - Banca toscana, sede di Firenze, agencia di città no.1: Piazza della Signoria 21-22-23 rosso, Via Condotta 53-55 rosso, 50122 Firenze, telefoni 276096, 284006. [Firenze: Superstudio, c1970], Catalog # 23 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9886811.
  - Esperienze. 1. Firenze: G & G Firenze, 1971., Catalog # 24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892131.
  - In. anno 2:n.2/3(1971:mar./giugno) Firenze: [s.n.], 1970-, Catalog # 26 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892156.
  - In. n.5(1972:magg/giugno) [Milano]: S.E.R.T., Catalog # 40 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892172.
  - In. n.7(1972:sett./ott.) [Milano]: S.E.R.T., Catalog # 43 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - In. n.8(1972:nov./dic.) [Milano]: S.E.R.T., Catalog # 46 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 7a Biennale di Parigi: Italia = 7e Biennale de Paris: Italie = 7th Paris Biennale: Italy / Commissario generale: Achille Bonito Oliva. Firenze: Centro Di, 1971., Catalog # 27; Biennale de Paris (7e: 1971) Italy (Box 1, Folder 31)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892204.
  - S-Space presents: vita, morte e miracoli dell'architettura = life, death and miracles of architecture: catalog festival n. 1, Nov. 9-11/1971, Space Electronic, Firenze / co-production 9999-Superstudio; (cover and design by 9999). [Italy: s.n., 1971], Catalog # 28 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892238.
  - Caro studente o cultore dell'ambiente = Dear student or environment cultivator ... [Italy: s.n., 1971], Catalog # 29 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9892278.
  - Architectural design: A.D. v.42:12(1971:Dec.) London: Standard Catalogue Co., 1971-, Catalog # 31 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/762642.
  - JAM: Projekte der Arthropoden zur Gestaltung der Zukunft / von James Burns. Köln: Phaidon-Verlags, c1971., Catalog # 32; Burns, Jim, 1926- (Box 1, Folder 35)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9893019.
  - January 25-29 1972 at the Architectural Association, 34-36 Bedford Square, London. London: [s.n.], 1972., Catalog # 34 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9893294.
  - Casabella. no.358(1971:nov.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/467504.
  - Casabella. no.361(1972:genn.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 33 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Casabella. no.363(1972:mar.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 36 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Casabella. no.366(1972:giugno) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 39 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Poster, "Italy: the new domestic landscape." Removed from Casabella. no.366(1972:giugno), Catalog # 39 (Box 9 (Broadside))
  - Casabella. no.367(1972:luglio) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 42.1 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Casabella. 369(1972:ag./sett.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 42.2 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Casabella. no.372(1972:dic.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 45 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Casabella. no.374(1973:febbr.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 42.3 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Casabella. n.376(1973:apr.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 53 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Casabella. no.377(1973:magg.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 42.4 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Casabella. no.380/381(1973:ag./sett.) [Milano: Domus, 1965- ], Catalog # 42.5 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Exhibition flyer, "Superstudio, Napoli, Lia Rumma / Studio d'Arte", 1972; Catalog # 35; Superstudio (Group) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Italy: the new domestic landscape; achievements and problems of Italian design. Edited by Emilio Ambasz. New York; Distributed by New York Graphic Society, Greenwich, Conn. [1972], Catalog # 38; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/5217260.
  - Summer session, 72, International Institute of Design [graphic]: 24 July-25 August: for information write enclosing details of background, interests and possible contributions to: Alvin Boyarsky, director I.I.D., 28 Upper Park Road, London NW3. [London: The Institute, 1972], Catalog # 41; International Institute of Design (Box 10 (Broadside))
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9893504.
  - Transparency of "Global Tools - 12 gennaio 1973" group portrait, Catalog # 48 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - L'invenzione della superficie neutra [graphic]: É il progetto di una mostra di environments ideato da Ettore Sottsass, jr., Archizoom associati, Superstudio, George Snowden, Clino Trini Castelli, con la collaborazione organizzativa della Abet Print ... A travelling exhibition of environments has been planned by Ettore Sottsass, Jr., Archizoom associati, Superstudio, George Snowden, and Clino Trini Castelli, with organizational assistance from Abet Print ... [Italy]: Abet Print, [1973], Catalog # 49 (Box 11 (Broadside))
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9893661.
  - Black and white group portrait photograph of Global Tools reunion, 1973; Catalog # 50 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Black and white group portrait photograph of Global Tools reunion, 1973; Catalog # 51 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Collage, "Manifesto per una mostra di design", 1973; Catalog # 52; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 12 (Broadside))
  - Fragmente aus einem persönlichen Museum: Superstudio. [Graz: Neue Galerie am Landemuseum Joanneum, 1973], Catalog # 54; Superstudio (Group) (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 102)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9901997.
  - Sottsass, Superstudio; mindscapes DQ89. An exhibition organized by Walker Art Center. Minneapolis, Walker Art Center [c1973], Catalog # 55 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9893707.
  - Gli abiti dell'imperatore / Luca Palazzoli. Milano: Luca Palazzoli, [1974], Catalog # 56; Palazzoli, Luca (Box 2, Folder 54)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9894208.
  - Global tools. anno 1:n.1(1974:giugno) Milano: [s.n.], 1974-1975., Catalog # 57.1 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9894079.
  - Global tools. anno 1:no.1(1975:genn.) Milano: [s.n.], 1974-1975., Catalog # 57.2 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Architettura radicale / Paola Navone, Bruno Orlandoni. Segrate: G. Milani, 1974., Catalog # 58; Navone, Paola (Box 2, Folder 57)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/1792324.
  - Che. 1(1974:ott.) Napoli: [s.n.], 1974-, Catalog # 59 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9895869.
  - Collage, "Natura morta all'ingresso del Superstudio, con vaso di Sottsass fiori di plasitca ecc.", 1974; Catalog # 61; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 13 (Broadside))
  - Dalla città al cucchiaio: saggi sulle nuove avanguardie nell'architettura e nel design / [di] Bruno Orlandoni e Giorgio Vallino. Torino: Studio Forma, 1977., Catalog # 62; Orlandoni, Bruno (Box 2, Folder 59)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9895885.
  - Spazioarte. anno 4:10/11(1977:giugno/ott.) Roma: [s.n.], 1974-, Catalog # 63 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9895907.
  - Biblioteca comunale di Certaldo, "L'esperienza": orientamenti attuali del lavoro artistico: Giuseppe Chiari, Piero Dorazio, Luciano Fabro, Fabio Mauri, Bruno Munari, Concetto Pozzati, Adolfo Natalini - Superstudio, Pino Tovaglia, Giuseppe Uncini: Certaldo, Palazzo Pretorio, 1 ottobre - 30 novembre 1977. Firenze: Clichés Parretti, 1977., Catalog # 64 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897294.
  - Superstudio: In-arch, Istituto nazionali [sic] di architettura: Roma, Palazzo Taverna, 20-23 marzo 1978. Firenze: Centro Di, 1978., Catalog # 65 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897350.
  - La memoria invece: tre mostre allo Studio Franca Pisani, Firenze, maggio 1978 / Adolfo Natalini. Firenze: [s.n., 1978], Catalog # 66; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 2, Folder 63)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897386.
  - Superstudio: La moglie di Lot e la coscienza di Zeno: la Biennale di Venezia 1978: utopia e crisi dell'antinatura: Intentzioni architettoniche in Italia / Superstudio. [Venezia?: s.n., 1978], Catalog # 67; Frassinelli, Piero (Box 2, Folder 64)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897428.
  - Modo. no.19(1979:magg.) [Milano: R.D.E. Ricerche Design, Catalog # 69 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897485.
  - Superstudio, una casa fatta (anche) di memoria = Superstudio, ein Haus (auch) aus Erinnerungen. Lübbecke: Uhle und Kleinann, [1979], Catalog # 70 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897519.
  - Superstudio-- storie con figure, 1966-73: a cura di Adolfo Natalini. [Florence, Italy?: Galleria Vera Biondi?, 1979], Catalog # 71 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897964.
  - Catalogo-- Sistemazione del design, Raccolta del design. [Milano]: Cooperativa Il Guado, [1979], Catalog # 72 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 103)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9897599.
  - Proposte di analisi su fenomeni delle culture marginali: mostra organizzata dal Comune di Bibbiena in collaborazione con "Ar.te & tecnica cooperativa," Bibbiena Sala communale, dicembre 1979. Firenze: Tipolitografia "G. Capponi, [1979], Catalog # 73 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898030.
  - Note in margine al Römerberg Project, 1979 / a cura di Adolfo Natalini/Superstudio. Firenze: Tipgrafia "G. Capponi," 1979, Catalog # 74 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898318.
  - Superstudio & radicals / edited by Superstudio & the Moriyama Editors Studio. Tokyo: Japan Interior Inc., 1982., Catalog # 75 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898365.
  - Superstudio, 1966-1982: storie, figure, architettura / a cura di Gianni Pettena. [Florence]: Electa Firenze, c1982., Catalog # 76 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/278149.
  - Dimui u-mashal: Supersṭudyo Firentseh / [otser, Iziḳah Gaʾon] = Metaphors and allegories: Superstudio Firenze / [curator, Izzika Gaon]. Yerushalayim: Muzeʾon Yiśraʾel, Yerushalayim, [1982], Catalog # 77 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/2713784.
  - La nuova stazione di Bologna (progetto) / Adolfo Natalini, Roberto Magris, Pierluigi Nicolin, Francesco Tomassi; scritti di Giampietro Martarelli e Vittorio Savi. [Firenze: s.n., 1983] (Firenze: Centro Stampa Palagi), Catalog # 78 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898432.
  - Figure di pietra = Figures of stone / Adolfo Natalini. Milano: Electa; New York: Rizzoli, c1984., Catalog # 79; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 2, Folder 74)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/391889.
  - Adolfo Natalini: obras y proyectos 1978-1984 / textos, Manuel Serrano Marzo, Vittorio Salvi, Paolo Portoghesi, Adolfo Natalini; Colegio Oficial de Arquitectos de Madrid, Comisión de Cultura, Insituto italiano di Madrid, Embajada de Italia, Escuela T.S. de Arquitectura de Madrid, Universidad Politécnica de Madrid. Madrid: Servicio de Publicaciones del Colegio Oficial de Arquitectos de Madrid, c1985., Catalog # 80 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898479.
  - Lithograph, "Rimini - Il Teatro e la Rocca da ovest", 1985; Catalog # 81; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 104)
  - Drawing, "P. L. Firenze" [Progetto per un isolato a Firenze - Assonometria], 1988; Catalog # 82; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 105)
  - Drawing, "P. L. Firenze" [Progetto per un isolato a Firenze - Pianta], 1988; Catalog # 83; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 106)
  - Anfione zeto. anno 1:no.0(1988) Roncade, Italy: Pagus Edizioni, 1988-, Catalog # 84 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/3813752.
  - Adolfo Natalini: architetture raccontate / Adolfo Natalini; introduzione di Pierluigi Nicolin; testi di Vittorio Savi. Milano: Electa, c1989., Catalog # 85; Savi, Vittorio, 1948- (Box 3, Folder 77)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898829.
  - Notes on the town squares of Italy / edited by Adolfo Natalini. [Greve in Chianti (Italy)]: Il Ferrone, c1989., Catalog # 86 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898625.
  - Appunti costruttivi: La palestra a Gorle di Adolfo Natalini / con un saggio di Vittorio Savi. Greve (Firenze): Il Ferrone, 1992., Catalog # 87 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    For more information see the corresponding catalog record: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/9898715.
  - Adolfo Natalini s. l.: Driade, 1993., Catalog # 88 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Drawing, "Manetstr. Leipzig" [Isolato sulla Manetstrasse - Leipzig], 1993; Catalog # 89; Natalini, Adolfo, 1941- (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 107)